- Ooh, those chicken wings smell amazing.
哦，那些鸡翅闻起来真香。
- No. No. No.
不，不，不。
[laughter]
[笑声]
No.
不。
- But you always give us a taste.
但你总是让我们尝尝。
- Not today. These are for Mr. Wigglesworth.
今天不行。这些是给威格斯沃斯先生的。
He's my toughest critic, and if he likes them
他是我最严厉的批评者，如果他喜欢它们
then I know they're good.
那么我就知道它们不错。
- Hmm. Tell me more.
嗯，多告诉我一些。
- Well, I really want to enter the Colorado Kids Cook-Off,
嗯，我真的很想参加科罗拉多儿童烹饪大赛，
and I'm thinking of putting these on my menu.
我正考虑把这些菜加入我的菜单。
- Oh.
哦。
Well, I hope he loves them.
希望他会喜欢它们。
- I know we will.
我知道我们会喜欢的。
- At least savor them!
至少要好好品尝！
- Savor what? Whoa!
品尝什么？哇！
- Don't make me tong you.
别逼我用夹子夹你。
These are for Mr. Wigglesworth.
这些是给Wigglesworth先生的。
- Oh, still worried about getting into that cook-off, huh?
哦，还在担心进入那个烹饪比赛，是吧？
- Yep. It's a big deal.
是的。这很重要。
First prize is a one-week apprenticeship
一等奖是一个为期一周的实习机会
with Chef Andre. He is a local chef
与安德烈大厨一起。他是一位本地厨师
who owns Bistro Andre.
拥有安德烈小酒馆。
- Wait, that's the hottest restaurant and nightclub
等等，那是博尔德最热门的餐厅和夜总会
in Boulder. So many famous singers
很多著名歌手
got their start there, and Chef Andre's the one who picks them.
都是从那里起步的，而安德烈大厨就是挑选他们的人。
I've always dreamed of singing there.
我一直梦想在那里唱歌。
- I've always dreamed of working there.
我一直梦想在那里工作。
To learn from Chef Andre would be incredible.
能向安德烈大厨学习将会非常不可思议。
- Indeed it would.
确实如此。
- Hello, sir. I was actually hoping
先生，您好。我其实想听听您对这些的看法。
to get your opinion on these.
那味道……很吸引人。
- That smells... intriguing.
我称它们为“再来一只翅膀”，因为吃了一个之后，你会想再吃一个。
- I call them, "Another Wing", because after you have one,
嗯，我们拭目以待。
you'll want another.
再来一个。
- Eh, we'll see about that.
再来一个！
Another.
啊-啊-啊！
[together] Another!
这是你第一次给我
- Aah-aah-ahh!
不止一个“嗯”。
- This is the first time you've given me
我认识你吗？
more than a, "hmm."
不止是“嗯”。
- Do I know you? - Yeah, Nicky Harper.
- 我认识你吗？ - 是的，我是Nicky Harper。
You usually hate everything I make.
你通常对我做的东西都不感冒。
- Enter the cook-off.
- 参加烹饪比赛吧。
You have a great shot at winning a week in my kitchen.
你有机会赢得在我厨房里的一周体验。
- Yes!
- 太好了！
Wait, your kitchen?
等等，你的厨房？
Bistro Andre is Chef Andre's place.
Bistro Andre是Chef Andre的餐厅。
- Indeed it is. - Oh, there you are.
- 确实如此。 - 哦，你在这里。
I see you've met my brother, Chef Andre.
看来你已经见过我的兄弟，Chef Andre了。
[together] Indeed we have.
确实如此。
[upbeat music]
- ♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na ♪
[whistling]
♪ ♪
- ♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na ♪ - ♪ Hey! ♪
- ♪ One, two ♪ - ♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na ♪ - ♪ One, two, three, four! ♪
[cheerful music]
- It is an honor to meet you, Chef Andre.
很荣幸见到您，安德烈大厨。
- Chef Andre. Until four years ago,
安德烈大厨，直到四年前，
he was Abner Wigglesworth.
他曾是Abner Wigglesworth。
- Wow, you are really identical.
哇，你们真的长得一模一样。
- Oh, it's simple to tell us apart.
哦，要区分我们很简单。
I'm the talented one.
我是那个有才华的。
- Just because I dedicated my life to teaching
仅仅因为我把一生奉献给了教学，
doesn't mean I'm un-talented.
并不意味着我没有才华。
- No, it's your lack of talent that makes you un-talented.
不，正是因为你缺乏才华，才让你显得没有才华。
That's why you're judging the qualifying rounds
这就是为什么你负责预选赛，
and I'm judging the finals.
而我负责决赛。
- Clearly you've got some stuff to Wiggles-work out here,
显然你在这里有些事情需要Wiggles-work解决，
so why are you doing the cook-off together?
那为什么你们要一起主持烹饪比赛？
[laughter]
[笑声]
- [together] Our mom made us.
我们妈妈让我们这么做的。
- And when one of my students wins,
当我的一个学生获胜时，
he'll have to admit my teaching has value.
他就不得不承认我的教学有价值。
- Well, at least you have one student who might be able
至少你有一个可能获胜的学生。
to win this thing. - Yes.
是的。
- Please. He doesn't even have a sous chef.
拜托，他连个副厨都没有。
- Oh, what a shame. It's required.
哦，真遗憾。这是必须的。
- No!
不！
- He has a sous chef. - I do?
- 他有副厨。 - 我有吗？
- Yes, me. - Me who?
- 是的，我。 - 我谁？
- Me, me.
- 我，我。
♪ Me, me, me, me me, me, me, me, me ♪
♪ 我，我，我，我 我，我，我，我，我 ♪
I also sing.
我还会唱歌。
- I hope to see you in the finals.
- 希望能在决赛见到你。
- Oh, well not only are you going to see him,
- 哦，不仅你会见到他，
but he's also going to win it with...
而且他还会和我一起赢得比赛……
♪ Me, me, me, me, me, me, me, me, me ♪
♪ 我，我，我，我，我，我，我，我，我 ♪
- He gets it. You sing.
- 他明白了。你唱吧。
- You'll have to get through my qualifying round first.
- 你得先通过我的预选赛。
- What was that? - Oh, just me supporting you.
- 那是什么？ - 哦，只是我在支持你。
- You weren't supporting me. You're doing this for you.
- 你不是在支持我。你这么做是为了你自己。
- For me? - Yes, you.
- 为了我？ - 是的，为了你。
♪ You, you, you, you, you, you, you, you ♪
♪ 你，你，你，你，你，你，你，你 ♪
You just wanna sing at his nightclub!
你只是想在他的夜总会唱歌！
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Well, yeah.
- 嗯，是的。
And you just wanna be able to cook in his restaurant.
而你只是想能在他的餐厅做饭。
It's a win-win.
这是双赢。
- Fine. You can be my sous chef.
好吧。你可以做我的副厨。
- Yes! And I'll be a great sous chef.
太好了！我会成为一个出色的副厨。
Quick question: what's a sous chef?
问个快问题：副厨是什么？
[laughter]
[笑声]
[rock music]
[摇滚音乐]
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Here's something we can talk about:
这里有件事我们可以聊聊：
if Dawn's helping Nicky out,
如果Dawn在帮Nicky的忙，
why did she have to change her name to Sue Chef?
为什么她得把名字改成Sue Chef？
Shouldn't she just be Dawn Chef?
她不应该直接叫Dawn Chef吗？
- No, "sous" is French for "under."
不，“sous”在法语中是“under”的意思。
She's Nicky's under-chef.
她是Nicky的副主厨。
- Oh, so in French, I'm wearing a pair
哦，所以在法语中，我穿着你的内衣。
of your sous-wear.
我更喜欢沉默。
- I preferred the silence.
这里有个问题：我们为什么不假装成对方呢？
- Here's a question: why don't we pretend
嗯，你已经在穿我的内衣了，所以你有个好的开始。
to be each other? - Well, you're already
我让你穿我的东西。
wearing my sous-wear, so you'd have a head start.
我不想穿你的任何东西。
- I'll let you wear something of mine.
鞋子怎么样？
- I don't want to wear anything of yours.
我拿一只鞋子能干什么？
- How about a shoe?
- 一双鞋怎么样？
- What am I gonna do with one shoe?
- 我一只鞋能干嘛？
- Oh, you're right. Here's the other one.
- 哦，你说得对。这里还有另一只。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Are you wearing two different shoes?
- 你穿了两只不同的鞋吗？
- I'm not wearing any shoes. I just gave them to you.
- 我没穿鞋。我只是把它们给了你。
- Guys, what are you arguing about?
- 伙计们，你们在争论什么？
- Dicky wants me to wear his two right shoes.
- Dicky想让我穿他的两只右鞋。
- Well, it sounds like a great idea.
- 嗯，听起来是个好主意。
- You want me to wear two right shoes?
- 你想让我穿两只右鞋？
- No, no, no, no. What your father meant was
不，不，不，不。你父亲的意思是
maybe you should try walking a mile in each other's shoes.
也许你应该试着穿上对方的鞋子走一英里。
You might learn to appreciate one another.
你可能会学会欣赏彼此。
- Right, Tom? - Uh, no.
对吧，汤姆？
I just thought it'd be fun to watch him walk in two right--
呃，不是。
Right, yeah, that's what I meant.
我只是觉得看他穿着两只右脚的鞋走路会很有趣——
[laughter]
对，没错，我就是这个意思。
- Okay, so how do I walk in your shoes?
笑声
- Uh... Well, you can start with my poetry journal.
好吧，那我怎么穿上你的鞋子？
- I don't know how my foot's gonna stay in there, but okay.
呃... 你可以从我的诗集开始。
So what do you want of mine?
那你想从我这里得到什么？
- Surprise me.
给我个惊喜。
- Boo! [laughter]
吓！
- Just give me your skateboard.
就把你的滑板给我吧。
[laughter]
Nothing good is ever gonna come of this.
这事儿不会有好结果的。
- Hey, I'm Abby. I'm really into skateboarding.
嘿，我是艾比。我非常喜欢滑板。
- Hi, I'm Ricky.
嗨，我是里基。
Big-time skateboarding aficionado.
滑板界的超级爱好者。
- I'm Norah. I love poetry.
我是诺拉。我热爱诗歌。
- And I'm Dicky,
- 我是Dicky，
a big-time poetry a-fish-o-nachos.
一个超级诗歌爱好者。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Hey. Maybe we can hang out sometime
- 嘿。也许我们可以找个时间一起出去
and talk about skateboarding. - And poetry.
聊聊滑板。 - 还有诗歌。
- That sounds great. - How about now?
- 听起来不错。 - 那现在怎么样？
- [together] Now? - [together] Now.
- [一起] 现在？ - [一起] 现在。
- [together] No. - [together] No?
- [一起] 不行。 - [一起] 不行？
- Uh, we can't.
- 呃，我们不行。
Because I have skateboarding practice.
因为我有滑板训练。
- And I have poetry practice.
- 我还有诗歌练习。
- [together] Now?
- [一起] 现在？
- [together] Now. - How about tomorrow?
- [一起] 现在。 - 那明天怎么样？
- Tomorrow's perfect.
- 明天很完美。
- It's a date.
- 那就这么定了。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- We'd better get to our practices.
- 我们最好去练习了。
- Whoa. You're not ready, dude.
- 哇，你还没准备好，伙计。
You don't want to embarrass yourself.
你不想让自己难堪吧。
Wait, how stupid do I look?
等等，我看起来有多傻？
I forgot my shoes.
我忘了带鞋子。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- And your poetry journals! [laughter]
- 还有你的诗集！[笑声]
♪♪
- Welcome to the qualifying round.
- 欢迎来到资格赛。
The winner shall go on to the Colorado Kids Cook-Off finals
胜者将进入科罗拉多儿童厨艺大赛决赛
and represent my class.
并代表我们班级。
Your challenge-- the perfect omelet.
你们的挑战——制作完美的煎蛋卷。
Now, spatulas up, and cook.
现在，拿起锅铲，开始烹饪。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- All right, you crack the eggs
好的，你来打鸡蛋
while I mince the scallions.
我则切葱花。
- On it.
好的。
[laughter]
笑声
- Make sure you don't get any shells in there.
确保不要让蛋壳掉进去。
[laughter]
笑声
And don't forget to add salt.
别忘了加盐。
- Got it.
知道了。
[laughter]
笑声
- Oh, but not too much salt
哦，但盐不要加太多
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Okay, salt has been added.
— 好了，盐已经加了。
- What are you doing?
— 你在干嘛？
[laughter]
[笑声]
Okay, if you want any chance of singing
好吧，如果你想有机会在安德烈大厨的夜总会唱歌，你就得守好自己的本分。
at Chef Andre's nightclub, you need to stay in your lane.
— 你看，我只是想——
- See, I'm just trying-- - Stay in you lane!
— 守好你自己的本分！
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Okay, jeez. Chill.
— 好了，天哪。冷静点。
I feel like I'm walking on egg shells.
我觉得我像是在踩鸡蛋壳。
- It's because you are.
- 就是因为你这样。
There are literally egg shells everywhere.
实际上，到处都是蛋壳。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Oh, superb spatula work, Flavio.
- 哦，弗拉维奥，你的铲子用得真好。
[laughter]
[笑声]
Hmph. [laughter]
哼。[笑声]
- "Hmph?" Wh-Why is he so hard on me?
- “哼？”他为什么对我这么严厉？
He's never gonna choose our omelet.
他永远不会选我们的煎蛋卷。
- You know what? I think I have an idea
- 你知道吗？我想我有个主意
of how to make this fair.
让这变得公平。
So, Mr. Wigglesworth, uh, when do you
那么，Wigglesworth先生，呃，你什么时候
when do you put on your blindfold?
你什么时候戴上眼罩？
- What blindfold?
- 什么眼罩？
Oh, I just thought you have such a refined palate
哦，我只是觉得你的味觉如此精致
that you can judge a dish without even seeing it.
以至于你可以不用看就能评判一道菜。
Oh, wait. That's your brother.
哦，等等。那是你哥哥。
- My palate is just as refined as his!
- 我的味觉和他一样精致！
Flavio, give me your sock! [laughter]
Flavio，把你的袜子给我！[笑声]
I've come to a decision.
我已经做出了决定。
This one is the clear winner.
这个显然是赢家。
- [together] Yes! - Spatch-five.
- [一起] 是的！ - 斯帕奇-五。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- The Harpers?
- 哈珀一家？
Sorry, Flavio.
对不起，弗拉维奥。
I hope this wasn't a fluke.
我希望这不是侥幸。
- It wasn't. We won't let you down, sir.
- 不是的。我们不会让你失望的，先生。
- Good, because the finals can be quite demanding.
- 很好，因为决赛会相当苛刻。
A full three-course meal in a very short amount of time.
要在非常短的时间内完成一顿完整的三分菜餐。
Therefore, you will be relying heavily on your sous chef.
因此，你们将非常依赖你们的副厨师。
- Don't worry. We got this.
- 别担心。我们能搞定。
Spatch-five.
斯帕奇-五。
Whoa! [thud]
哇！[砰]
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Fork, Flavio!
- 叉子，弗拉维奥！
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Okay, if you're gonna convince Norah you're a poet,
- 好吧，如果你想让诺拉相信你是个诗人，
we have to get you familiar with the fundamentals.
我们得让你熟悉一下基本要素。
So let's start with some rhyming.
所以让我们从押韵开始。
- Easy enough. - Okay.
- 很简单。 - 好的。
I'll start a rhyme, and you finish it.
我先开始一句，你来接完它。
While sitting under the tree, little Johnny was stung by a...
坐在树下时，小约翰尼被一只...
- Jellyfish.
水母。
- Okay, if we want any shot in the finals,
好的，如果我们想在决赛中有所作为，
you need basic sous chef skills.
你需要掌握基本的副厨技能。
Now, let's start with something so simple
现在，我们从一些简单到
that a monkey could do it.
连猴子都能做的事情开始。
Juicing a lime. - Yes, Chef.
榨青柠汁。
Oh, oh, oh, oh! - Aah! Aah!
哦，哦，哦，哦！
It's in the ducts! - Aah!
它在管道里！
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Okay, time for some skateboarding basics.
好的，现在来学习滑板的基础。
This is a skateboard. - Noted.
这是一个滑板。- 明白了。
- Okay, now, standing on it.
好的，现在站上去。
- Piece of cake.
小菜一碟。
- Okay, so limes aren't your thing.
好吧，看来挤酸橙不是你的强项。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Aah! It's in the shin.
- 啊！撞到胫骨了。
- My bad.
- 我的错。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Okay, let's move on to cracking eggs.
好的，接下来我们学习打鸡蛋。
Now, the trick is it's all in the wrist.
现在，诀窍全在手腕上。
Just-- - Okay.
就——
[laughter]
好的。
- A little too much wrist. - I thought you said
（笑声）
a monkey could do this stuff.
——手腕用力过猛了。
- Because a monkey could. [laughter]
我以为你说猴子都能做这个。
- You really think this is gonna make me sound like a poet?
——因为猴子确实能。（笑声）
- Let's hope. On your left hand
——你真觉得这能让我听起来像诗人？
are types of poetry. On your right are adjectives.
——希望如此。你的左手边是不同类型的诗歌，右手边是形容词。
So when Norah asks you about poetry,
所以当诺拉问你关于诗歌的问题时，
just say, "I find," and then one word from the left
就說，“我發現，”然後從左邊選一個詞，
and one from the right.
再從右邊選一個詞。
Awesome. I find...
太棒了。我發現...
sonnets...
十四行詩...
inspiring.
令人鼓舞。
Nailed it. - You've earned this, Mr. Poet.
做到了。 - 你贏得了這個，詩人先生。
And I think you know it.
我想你知道的。
Nope, it's just for holding.
不，只是用來拿著。
[laughter]
（笑聲）
- Okay, I think I found a way to use your...
好吧，我想我找到了一個方法來使用你的...
let's call it skill, in the kitchen.
让我们称之为厨房里的技艺吧。
Now, do what comes naturally.
现在，做你自然而然会做的事。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Look at me! I'm cooking!
- 看我！我在做饭！
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Dude, that 540 was sick.
- 伙计，那个540度旋转太酷了。
Look at me. I'm skateboarding!
看我。我在滑板！
- [together] We're ready. - [together] Yes!
- [一起]我们准备好了。 - [一起]是的！
[laughter]
[笑声]
[rock music]
[摇滚音乐]
- So, Dicky, what do you think about haikus?
- 那么，Dicky，你怎么看俳句？
- Well, haikus are okay, but I find...
- 嗯，俳句还可以，但我发现...
Free verse...exhilarating.
自由诗...令人振奋。
[laughter] - Wow.
[笑声] - 哇。
You know so much. - I have all the best words...
你懂得真多。 - 我掌握了所有最好的词汇...
right in the palm of my hand.
就在我的手掌心里。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Ricky, what happened to your head?
- Ricky，你的头怎么了？
It makes you look so extreme.
这让你看起来非常酷。
- Yeah, got it grinding on my sweet deck.
- 是啊，我在我的酷炫滑板上磨蹭。
- Whoa, you are a skateboard aficionado.
哇，你是个滑板爱好者。
- [both sighing]
【两人同时叹气】
- Walk a mile in each other's shoes.
设身处地为对方着想。
So simple, yet so effective.
简单却很有效。
- Unless they're yours. No one could walk a mile
除非那是你的鞋。没人能穿着那雪橇走一英里。
in those sleds.
好吧，到时候你想让我打死蜘蛛时，这雪橇可就派上大用场了。
- Okay, well, those sleds are gonna come in really handy
我什么时候让你打死过蜘蛛？
when you want me to kill a spider.
嗯，大概两秒后。
- When have I ever asked you to kill a spider?
请别尖叫。
- Hmm, about two seconds from now.
【尖叫声】
Please don't scream.
请不要尖叫。
- [screams]
（尖叫声）
- So, do you, like, grind rails?
那么，你喜欢滑轨吗？
- Do I, like, grind rails?
我，喜欢滑轨吗？
Next time we hang, I'll, like, grind that rail.
下次我们出去玩，我会，比如，滑那个轨道。
- That'd be rad.
那会很酷。
- And I will read one of my... Limericks... Eloquent.
而我将朗读我的... 五行诗... 优雅的。
[laughter]
（笑声）
Eloquent limericks.
优雅的五行诗。
- [together] How about now? - [together] Now?
（一起）现在怎么样？（一起）现在？
- [together] Now. - [together] No.
- [一起] 现在。 - [一起] 不。
- [together] No?
- [一起] 不？
- Uh, I have skateboarding practice.
- 呃，我有滑板练习。
- And I have poetry practice.
- 我还有诗歌练习。
- [together] Again? - [together] Again.
- [一起] 又来？ - [一起] 又来。
- How about tomorrow? - [together] Tomorrow's perfect.
- 明天怎么样？ - [一起] 明天很合适。
- [together] Perfect.
- [一起] 合适。
- Perfect? What was I thinking?
- 合适？我在想什么？
I just promised to read a poem tomorrow.
我刚刚答应了明天读一首诗。
- Oh, really? Read a poem?
- 哦，真的吗？读诗？
I just promised to, like, grind down that railing.
我刚刚承诺要，比如，磨平那个栏杆。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Yeah, you're gonna break, like, a lot of bones.
- 是的，你会断掉很多骨头。
[rock music]
[摇滚音乐]
- Students, welcome-- - To the finals prep meeting.
- 同学们，欢迎-- - 参加决赛准备会议。
Who knows what "farm to table" is?
谁知道“从农场到餐桌”是什么意思？
- Ooh!
- 哦！
- I know what "singer-to-stage" is.
- 我知道“从歌手到舞台”是什么意思。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Farm-to-table is when the food on the table at a restaurant
- “从农场到餐桌”是指餐厅桌上的食物
comes straight from local farms.
直接来自当地农场。
- Exactly. Now, on your tablets,
- 没错。现在，在你们的平板上
you will find a dossier of how the ingredients are sourced
你们会找到一份资料，说明食材是如何从你们提交的菜单中采购的
from the menus you submitted.
来源情况。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Oh, check it out. The dossier has a biography
- 哦，看看这个。资料里有我们要供应的这只鸡的传记
of the chicken we're going to serve.
哦，猜猜它的名字叫什么。
Oh, guess what his name is.
- 史蒂夫。
- Steve.
- 谁会给鸡取名叫史蒂夫？
- Who would name a chicken Steve?
- 谁会给鸡取名？- 是尼基！他的名字叫尼基。
- Who would name a chicken? - It's Nicky!
- 谁会给一只鸡取名字？ - 是Nicky！
His name is Nicky.
他的名字是Nicky。
[laughter]
[笑声]
Oh, and check out Chicken Nicky having fun on the farm.
哦，看看鸡Nicky在农场玩得多开心。
He gets coriander foot soaks, daily massages,
他享受香菜足浴，每天都有按摩，
oh, and even barnyard movie nights
哦，还有和他的鸡伙伴们的谷仓电影之夜
with his chicken compadres.
和他的鸡伙伴们一起。
- Chicken Nicky's got a better life than you.
- 鸡Nicky的生活比你好。
And better legs.
还有更好的腿。
- Steve.
- Steve。
[rock music]
摇滚音乐
♪ ♪
- Wow. You guys are really doing this
哇。你们真的在做这种‘设身处地为对方着想’的事情
"walk a mile in each other's shoes" thing
就是为了给一些女孩留下印象？
just to impress some girls?
是的。而且我们快疯了！
- Yep. And we're freakin' out!
别担心。在你和我之间，
- Don't worry. Between you and me,
作为你的我和作为我的你，
and me as you, and you as me,
我们四个人中的一个会想出办法解决这个问题的。
one of the four of us will come up with a way out of this.
[笑声]
[laughter]
他们找不到出路的。但回到鸡尼基的话题上。
- They're not gonna find a way.
- 他们不会找到办法的。
But back to Chicken Nicky.
但回到鸡尼基的话题。
[knocking]
[敲门声]
- Hey, Nicky. It's me, Chicken Nicky.
- 嘿，尼基。是我，鸡尼基。
- Chicken Nicky, what are you doing here?
- 鸡尼基，你在这里做什么？
- Well, I know you've seen what a great life I have,
- 嗯，我知道你已经看到了我有多么美好的生活，
so I thought you might wanna walk a mile in my chicken feet.
所以我想你可能想穿上我的鸡脚走一英里。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Tingly. And it smells good, too.
- 感觉刺刺的。而且闻起来也很好。
- That's the coriander.
- 那是香菜的味道。
On Thursdays, they add a little paprika.
每周四，他们会加一点辣椒粉。
- [together] Paprika Thursdays!
- [一起] 辣椒粉星期四！
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Ah, you've got the life, Chicken Nicky.
- 啊，你真是过着鸡的生活，鸡尼基。
- Yep. Cluck!
- 是的。咯咯！
Really work that wing.
真的要好好利用那翅膀。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- [together] Aah.
- [一起] 啊。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Cluck!
- 咯咯！
[laughter]
笑声
- That was the best day ever, Chicken Nicky.
那是有史以来最好的一天，小鸡尼基。
What are we doing tomorrow?
我们明天要做什么？
- Oh, tomorrow we're going from farm to table.
哦，明天我们要从农场到餐桌。
- What table? - The eating table.
什么餐桌？
That's where all us chickens end up.
吃饭的餐桌。
- Us?
那是我们所有鸡最终的去处。
I'm not a chicken.
我们？
[screams]
我不是鸡。
I'm freakin' out!
我吓坏了！
♪ ♪
[rock music]
- Welcome to the finals of the Colorado Kids Cook-Off.
- 欢迎来到科罗拉多儿童烹饪大赛的决赛。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Nicky, what are you doing with your neck?
- 尼基，你脖子在干嘛？
- Nothing. It's just a--Cluck!
- 没什么。只是——咯！
It's a crick.
是扭到了。
- Ready, chefs? And, cook.
- 准备好了吗，厨师们？开始烹饪。
- It's Thursday. Don't forget the paprika.
- 今天是星期四。别忘了放辣椒粉。
[screams] I can't do this.
[尖叫] 我做不到。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- What? What are you doing?
- 什么？你在做什么？
- I can't cook Chicken Nicky. - Why not?
- 我做不了鸡肉尼基。 - 为什么不行？
- Last night, I had a dream,
- 昨晚，我做了一个梦，
and I realized chicken... is a chicken.
然后我意识到鸡肉...就是鸡。
- Well, of course chicken is a chicken.
- 当然，鸡肉就是鸡。
And beef is a cow. - Beef is a cow?
牛肉是牛？ - 牛肉是牛？
I can't cook meat at all.
我根本不能烹饪肉类。
- But your whole menu is meat.
- 但你的整个菜单都是肉类。
- I'm sorry, Dawn. I don't wanna ruin your chances
- 对不起，Dawn。我不想毁了你的机会
at singing, but I'm out.
在唱歌方面，但我退出了。
- Come on, Nicky. Stop being such a chicken.
- 来吧，Nicky。别这么胆小。
- Cluck! - Sorry, poor choice of words.
- 咯咯！ - 抱歉，用词不当。
[laughter]
[笑声]
[rock music]
[摇滚音乐]
- And just like that, Skateboard Ricky can't
- 就这样，滑板Ricky不能
grind down the railing.
沿着栏杆滑行。
- And poet Dicky can't recite a poem
- 诗人Dicky不能朗诵一首诗
because he has a sore throat.
因为他喉咙痛。
- Now remember, you know how weak we get around these girls,
- 现在记住，你知道我们在这些女孩面前有多脆弱，
but it's important to stick to the plan.
但坚持计划很重要。
- Agreed. We have to stay strong.
- 同意。我们必须保持坚强。
- Hi, Dicky! - Wanna hear a poem?
- 嗨，Dicky！ - 想听一首诗吗？
- What are you doing? We're supposed to stay strong.
- 你在做什么？我们应该保持坚强。
- Hi, Ricky. - I'm goin' grinding.
- 嗨，Ricky。 - 我要去滑栏杆。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- What are you doing?
- 你在做什么？
- The only thing you taught me to do.
- 你唯一教我做的事。
Now, will you come up here and help?
现在，你能上来帮忙吗？
- No.
- 不。
- Fine. You can give up on your passion,
好吧。你可以放弃你的热情，
but I'm not giving up on mine.
但我不会放弃我的。
I'm gonna win this competition, with or without you.
我要赢得这场比赛，无论有没有你。
Because I want the chance for Chef Andre to hear me sing.
因为我想要让安德烈大厨听到我唱歌的机会。
- Yeah, but without me, what are the odds
是啊，但没有我，这实际上发生的可能性有多大？
of that actually happening?
说得好。
- Good point.
这可能是安德烈大厨听到我唱歌的唯一机会。
This might be my only shot for Chef Andre to hear me sing.
♪ 我把蔬菜放进这个切片机 ♪
♪ I put the veggies in this slicer ♪
♪ 我切一次，然后我再切两次 ♪
♪ I slice them once and then I slice them twice-er ♪
这两位用的手法真不寻常。
- Unusual techniques, these two have.
- 这两位的手法真是不寻常。
One sings to the vegetables,
一个对着蔬菜唱歌，
the other cuddles them.
另一个则拥抱它们。
- Hmph.
- 哼。
- Be careful with that thing.
- 用那东西时要小心。
[metallic grinding]
[金属磨擦声]
Look at all the vegetables you're wasting!
看看你浪费了多少蔬菜！
[laughter]
[笑声]
It's enough for a whole meal.
足够做一整餐了。
A whole meal? That's it.
一整餐？就这样。
Genius.
天才。
- You're back?
- 你回来了？
- You bet your sweet potatoes, I'm back.
- 你敢赌你的甜薯，我回来了。
And I have a way to stay true to myself and win this.
而且我有办法保持自我并赢得这个。
- Yes!
- 太好了！
♪ We are so gonna win this-- ♪
♪ 我们肯定会赢这个-- ♪
- But you gotta stop singing.
- 但你得停止唱歌。
- Oh, did I do it? - Not even close, dude.
- 哦，我唱了吗？ - 差得远呢，伙计。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Where are the girls?
- 女孩们去哪儿了？
- They left when you were halfway down the railing
他们离开时你正滑到栏杆中间，
screaming, "Mommy! Mommy! Mommy!"
大喊着：“妈妈！妈妈！妈妈！”
[laughter]
（笑声）
- Understandable. - What happened?
可以理解。
- We did what you said and walked in each other's shoes.
发生了什么？
- Not your best parenting advice.
我们按照你说的，尝试站在对方的立场上。
[laughter]
这不是你最好的育儿建议。
- See? Walking in two right shoes
（笑声）
doesn't sound so stupid now, does it?
看吧？穿着两只右脚鞋
- Still does, Tom.
现在听起来没那么蠢了，是吧？
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Spider! [screams]
- 蜘蛛！[尖叫]
[laughter]
[笑声]
[rock music]
[摇滚音乐]
- Mmm! Mmm.
- 嗯！嗯。
- Everyone else made meat.
- 其他人做的都是肉菜。
- Don't worry. My vegetarian meal
- 别担心。我的素食餐
is just as delicious as any meat menu.
和任何肉类菜单一样美味。
- And what have you made for me today?
- 你今天为我做了什么？
- I have stuffed peppers, a chickpea pot pie,
- 我有填馅辣椒，鹰嘴豆馅饼，
and truffle mac and cheese.
还有松露通心粉和奶酪。
- Edible.
- 可食用的。
Short for "incredible."
缩写为“难以置信”。
Short for "some of the most incredible
缩写为“我吃过的最不可思议的
vegetarian dishes I have ever had."
素食菜肴之一。”
Oh, the competition was stiff,
哦，竞争很激烈，
but there is one clear winner.
但有一个明显的赢家。
[chuckles] Maggie.
[轻笑] Maggie。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Wait. But--But you said
- 等等。但是——但是你说过
Nicky made the most incredible vegetarian dishes
Nicky做的素食菜肴是你吃过的最不可思议的。
you've ever had.
你吃过的最不可思议的。
- But meat makes the meal.
- 但肉才是主菜。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- You're wrong!
- 你错了！
all: [gasps]
大家：[惊呼]
- Go on.
- 继续。
- Vegetables can be a meal.
- 蔬菜也可以是一顿饭。
Food isn't a one-size-fits-all.
食物不是一刀切的。
Some people like hamburgers. Some people like veggie burgers.
有些人喜欢汉堡，有些人喜欢素食汉堡。
That's the great thing about food.
这就是食物的美妙之处。
Everyone can choose for themselves.
每个人都可以为自己做选择。
- ♪ Choose for themselves ♪
- ♪ 为自己做选择 ♪
- Not the time, Dawn.
- 不是时候，Dawn。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Oh, well, in that case, I still choose Maggie's.
- 哦，那样的话，我还是选Maggie的。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Wow. Maybe I'm lying to myself
- 哇。也许我一直在自欺欺人
about being a chef.
关于成为一名厨师。
- No, you're not. You're a great chef, Nicky.
- 不，你没有。你是个很棒的厨师，Nicky。
- No, you're not.
不，你不是。
You're a really great chef, Nicky.
你真的是一个很棒的厨师，Nicky。
The best in the class, whatever you choose to cook.
无论你选择做什么菜，你都是班上最好的。
- Then why are you so hard on me?
那为什么你对我这么严格？
- Because I want you to live up to your full potential.
因为我希望你能发挥出你的全部潜力。
I'm hard on you because I believe in you.
我对你严格是因为我相信你。
- Really?
真的吗？
- And I'm hard you because I believe in you.
我对你严格是因为我相信你。
- Really? - No, Mom made me say it.
真的吗？
[laughter]
不，妈妈让我这么说的。
- I'm really glad you didn't give up on your passion.
我真的很高興你沒有放棄你的熱情。
- Well, I'm really sad I ruined your chance to pursue yours.
嗯，我真的很難過我毀了你追求自己夢想的機會。
- Who says you ruined it?
誰說你毀了它？
♪ Oh, how I would love to sing at-- ♪
♪哦，我多麼希望能在一一唱歌♪
- Wrong Wigglesworth.
錯的威格斯沃斯。
- ♪ Oh, how I-- ♪
♪哦，我一一♪
That was the right Wigglesworth, right?
那是正確的威格斯沃斯，對吧？
[laughter]
[笑聲]
Come back!
回來！
- Shall we?
我們開始吧？
- We shall.
我们开始吧。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- ♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na ♪
♪ 呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐 ♪
♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na ♪
[whistling]
[口哨声]
♪ ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 耶，耶，耶，耶，耶 ♪
- ♪ Yeah! ♪
♪ 耶！ ♪
- ♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 耶，耶，耶，耶，耶 ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 耶，耶，耶，耶 ♪
- ♪ Yeah! ♪
♪ 耶！ ♪